A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), Office Files of Christine Wing FA593
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ), Human Rights and International Cooperation (HRIC), Office Files of Christine Wing
1981-1998, bulk 1995-1998
1995-1998
Rockefeller Archive Center
Wing, Christine B., 1949-
Ford Foundation
FA593
2.62 Cubic Feet 2 record storage boxes.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement
Arranged in 2 series by file type.
Collection arrangement is as follows:
Series I. Grant Work Files, 1992-1998
Series II. Miscellaneous Files, 1981-1995
Scope and Contents
Contains grant work files and miscellaneous files.
Biographical / Historical
Christine Wing is a strategist, scholar, activist, and educator within the fields of philanthropy and international peace and security. From 1995 to 2004, she worked as a Program Officer at the Ford Foundation.
Wing joined the Ford Foundation in 1995 as a Program Officer in the International Affairs Program. Following the Foundation's program reorganization in 1996, Wing was moved into the Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ) Human Rights and International Cooperation unit (HRIC). While a Program Officer in the HRIC, she focused on the following initiatives: disarmament and the control of weapons, reduction in the amount of society's resources dedicated to military purposes, and support for local and regional capacity to address peace and conflict issues (Reflection and Close-Out Memo: Program on International Peace and Security, Human Rights and International Cooperation Unit, November 29, 2002, Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 13949-17726 (FA739F), Report 017092). Wing moved to the Governance and Civil Society unit of PSJ in 2002.
Prior to joining the Ford Foundation, Wing worked at the American Friends Service Committee (AFSC) from 1979 to 1989, first as the organization's National Representative for Economic Rights and then as Coordinator for the National Disarmament Program.
Wing started consulting for foundations, nonprofits, and international organizations in 2006 and started Chris Wing Consulting in 2016. She also worked as an adjunct professor and researcher at New York University between 2005 and 2015.
Wing is a member of the Board of Directors for the Arms Control Association. She completed her undergraduate education at Wellesley College, earned a Master's Degree in city and regional planning from the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, and earned a Ph.D. in international security studies from the Woodrow Wilson School of Public and International Affairs at Princeton University.
- Grant Work Files, 1992-1998; I
  Arrangement
  Alphabetical
  - ACCORD, 1997 (Box 1)
  - African Strategic and Peace Research Group, 1997 (Box 1)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Arias Foundation, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Arms Control Association, 1995-1997 (Box 1)
  - BASIC, 1994-1997 (Box 1)
  - Bonn International Center for Conversion, 1995-1997 (Box 1)
  - Columbia University, 1995-1997 (Box 1)
  - Cornell University, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - Fund for Peace (ACCESS), 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - Institute for War and Peace Reporting, 1993-1998 (Box 1)
  - International Institute for Strategic Studies, 1992-1997 (Box 1)
  - Institute of East-West Studies, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - International Peace Academy, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - International Peace Academy, 1995-1997 (Box 1)
  - International Peace Academy, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - Monterey Institute of International Studies, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - Nautilus of America Inc., 1996-1998 (Box 1)
  - Henry L. Stimson Center, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Henry L. Stimson Center, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Henry L. Stimson Center, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - University of Southampton (1/2), 1996-1997 (Box 2)
  - University of Southampton (2/2), 1996-1997 (Box 2)
  - United Nations, 1996-1998 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous Files, 1981-1995; II
  - Beijing Conference, 1995 (Box 2)
  - BASIC -- Conference on Light Weapons, 1995 October 21-23 (Box 2)
  - Program Review -- History of International Peace Grants, 1981-1990 (Box 2)